Guide to the Time Inc. Books Group 1963-1988, 2015 MS 3009-RG 28
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Group Vice President Files, 1963-1988; 14.5 Linear feet in 16 record cartons
  - Subseries I.B. International Files, 1968-1988; 4.5 Linear feet in 6 record cartons
    - Books and Arts and Associates: Raise Review, 1976-1980 (Offsite-box 3432, Folder 23)
    - Books and Arts and Associates: Summaries of Publishing Activities, 1974 (Offsite-box 3432, Folder 24)
    - Asia: China, 1971-1981 (Offsite-box 3432, Folder 25-27)
    - Asia: Hong Kong, 1976-1981 (Offsite-box 3432, Folder 28-29)
    - Asia: India, 1979 (Offsite-box 3432, Folder 30)
    - Asia: Indonesia, 1974-1979 (Offsite-box 3432, Folder 31)
    - Asia: Japan: General, 1971-1975 (Offsite-box 3432, Folder 32-34)
    - Asia: Japan: General, 1976-1985 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 1-6)
    - Asia: Japan: Children's Encyclopedia, 1973 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 7)
    - Asia: Japan: Direct-to-Consumer Sales, 1970-1973 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 8-9)
    - Asia: Japan: Fulfillment, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 10)
    - Asia: Japan: Incorporation, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 11)
    - Asia: Japan: Ingleton, Nicholas, 1980 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 12)
    - Asia: Japan: Ingleton, Nicholas [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
    - Asia: Japan: K. K. Pacifica (Japanese trade company), 1976-1979 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 13-14)
    - Asia: Japan: Medical Company: Board Memorandum, 1978 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 15)
    - Asia: Japan: NHK Series (Japan Broadcasting Corporation), 1973 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 16)
    - Asia: Japan: Seibu Time Company Ltd., 1983-1986 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 17-21)
    - Asia: Japan: Seibu Time Company Ltd. [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
    - Asia: Japan: Shingakusha, 1971-1977 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 22-23)
    - Asia: Japan: Teijin-Time, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 24-30)
    - Asia: Japan: Teijin-Time [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
    - Asia: Japan: Telephone Sales, 1974 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 31)
    - Asia: Japan: Time Inc. and Japanese Book Club, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 32-33)
    - Asia: Japan: Time-Life Communications, 1977-1979 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 34-35)
    - Asia: Japan: Time-Life Educational Program, 1971-1974 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 36)
    - Asia: Japan: Time-Life Educational Systems Co. Ltd., 1972 (Offsite-box 3433, Folder 37)
    - Asia: Japan: Time-Life Educational System: English Language Course, 1975-1979 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 1)
    - Asia: Japan: Time-Life Kyoiku Shuppan, 1979 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 2)
    - Asia: Japan: Time-Life Microsonics, 1978-1980 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 3-4)
    - Asia: Japan: Time-Life Tosho Hambai Kabushiki Kaisha, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 5-6)
    - Asia: Korea: General [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
    - Asia: Korea: Hankook Ilbo Time-Life, 1973-1979 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 7-10)
    - Asia: Korea: Hankook Ilbo Time-Life [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
    - Asia: Philippines, 1968-1981 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 11)
    - Asia: Russia, 1972-1978 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 12)
    - Asia: Russia [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
    - Asia: Singapore, 1971-1976 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 13-14)
    - Canada, 1981-1986 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 15)
    - Europe: Reorganization, 1978-1983 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 16)
    - Europe: Strategic Plan, 1985 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 17)
    - Europe: England/UK: Andre Deutsch Ltd., 1969-1975 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 18-20)
    - Europe: England/UK: BBC, 1969-1975 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 21-22)
    - Europe: England/UK: Beazley, Mitchell, 1971-1974 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 23)
    - Europe: England/UK: Harrow House Limited, 1977-1979 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 24)
    - Europe: England/UK: Harrow House Limited [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
    - Europe: England/UK: London, 1973-1983 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 25-26)
    - Europe: England/UK: Trewin Copplestone Ltd., 1980 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 27)
    - Europe: Finland, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 28)
    - Europe: France: Editions du Fanal, 1978 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 29)
    - Europe: France: Editions Robert Laffont: General, 1972-1977 (Offsite-box 3434, Folder 30-39)
    - Europe: France: Editions Robert Laffont: General, 1978-1983 (Offsite-box 3435, Folder 1-6)
    - Europe: France: Editions Robert Laffont: Board of Directors, 1969-1978 (Offsite-box 3435, Folder 7-9)
    - Europe: France: Editions Robert Laffont: Films, 1969-1974 (Offsite-box 3435, Folder 10)
    - Europe: France: Editions Robert Laffont: Financial, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 3435, Folder 11)
    - Europe: France: Editions Robert Laffont: Optidisc, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 3435, Folder 12)
    - Europe: France: Editions Robert Laffont: Recapitalization, 1978-1979 (Offsite-box 3435, Folder 13)
    - Europe: France: Medsi Group, 1978-1983 (Offsite-box 3435, Folder 14-15)
    - Europe: France: Paris Office, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3435, Folder 16)
    - Europe: Germany: General, 1976-1980 (Offsite-box 3435, Folder 17)
    - Europe: Germany: Christian Verlag, 1978-1982 (Offsite-box 3435, Folder 18-19)
    - Europe: Germany: Rowohlt Taschenbuch, 1972-1983 (Offsite-box 3435, Folder 20-22)
    - Europe: Italy: Mondadori, 1969-1972 (Offsite-box 3435, Folder 23-24)
    - Europe: The Netherlands, 1971-1985 (Offsite-box 3435, Folder 25-31)
    - Europe: Spain: Salvat Ediclub, 1968-1979 (Offsite-box 3436, Folder 1-5)
    - Latin America: General, 1968-1978 (Offsite-box 3436, Folder 6-7)
    - Latin America: Brazil: General, 1983 (Offsite-box 3436, Folder 8)
    - Latin America: Brazil: Medsi, 1981 (Offsite-box 3436, Folder 9a)
    - Latin America: Brazil: Rio de Janeiro, 1980 (Offsite-box 3436, Folder 9b)
    - Latin America: King, Robert H. [RESTRICTED], 1973 (Offsite-box R64)
    - Latin America: Management Operations Committee, 1975 (Offsite-box 3436, Folder 10)
    - Latin America: Mexico: General, 1971-1984 (Offsite-box 3436, Folder 11-16)
    - Latin America: Mexico: Organizacion Editorial Novaro: General, 1972-1977 (Offsite-box 3436, Folder 17-24)
    - Latin America: Mexico: Organizacion Editorial Novaro: General, 1978-1983 (Offsite-box 3437, Folder 1-7)
    - Latin America: Mexico: Organizacion Editorial Novaro: General [RESTRICTED], 1979-1982 (Offsite-box R64)
    - Latin America: Mexico: Organizacion Editorial Novaro: Board Memorandum, 1972 (Offsite-box 3437, Folder 8)
    - Latin America: Overseas Educational Society, 1971-1975 (Offsite-box 3437, Folder 9-10)
    - Latin America: Overseas Educational Society [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
    - Middle East: Egypt, 1976 (Offsite-box 3437, Folder 11)
    - Middle East: Iran: General, 1977 (Offsite-box 3437, Folder 12)
    - Middle East: Iran: Ellis, Bob, 1976-1981 (Offsite-box 3437, Folder 13)
    - Middle East: Iran: Board Memoranda, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3437, Folder 14-15)
    - Middle East: Israel, 1974-1983 (Offsite-box 3437, Folder 16-17)
    - SOPAC (South Pacific) / Australia, 1971-1979 (Offsite-box 3437, Folder 18-19)
  - Subseries I.C. Subsidiary Files, 1965-1987; 5 Linear feet in 7 record cartons
    The Subsidiary Files document the executive oversight of book publishing, subscription, or direct marketing companies acquired by Time Inc. Records include the strategic plans for the subsidiaries and files on publishing or sales projects. Some of the general files for subsidiaries have board meeting minutes and materials. Board records from Time-Life Books, Inc. originally were included with the other subsidiary files instead of with the administrative files. Items of interest include a memorandum stating that Time Inc. has no intention or interest in selling publisher Little, Brown and Company to prospective buyers.
    - Book-of-the-Month Club: General, 1977-1984 (Offsite-box 3437, Folder 20-27)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club: General, 1984 (Offsite-box 3438, Folder 1-2)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club: Board of Directors, 1974-1981 (Offsite-box 3438, Folder 3-9)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club: Fitzgerald, Ed, 1977-1980 (Offsite-box 3438, Folder 10)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club: Goals (Strategic Planning), 1981-1984 (Offsite-box 3438, Folder 11)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club: Personnel, 1978-1983 (Offsite-box 3438, Folder 12-13)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club: Silverman, Al, 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 3438, Folder 14)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club: Wiegers, Betsy, 1977-1979 (Offsite-box 3438, Folder 15)
    - General Learning Corporation, 1965, 1974 (Offsite-box 3438, Folder 16-17)
    - Haverhill's: General, 1971-1974 (Offsite-box 3438, Folder 18-21)
    - Haverhill's: Acquisition, 1971 (Offsite-box 3438, Folder 22)
    - Haverhill's: Board of Directors Meetings and Memoranda, 1971-1974 (Offsite-box 3438, Folder 23-25)
    - Haverhill's: Legal, 1971-1975 (Offsite-box 3438, Folder 26)
    - Little, Brown and Company: General, 1968-1986 (Offsite-box 3439, Folder 1-17)
    - Little, Brown and Company: General [RESTRICTED], 1971-1973 (Offsite-box R64)
    - Little, Brown and Company: Board of Directors Meetings and Memoranda, 1969-1981 (Offsite-box 3439, Folder 18-22)
    - Little, Brown and Company: College Division, 1986 (Offsite-box 3439, Folder 23)
    - Little, Brown and Company: College Hill Press, 1986 (Offsite-box 3439, Folder 24)
    - Little, Brown and Company: Dolan, Kevin, 1985 (Offsite-box 3439, Folder 25)
    - Little, Brown and Company: Goals, 1982-1983 (Offsite-box 3439, Folder 26)
    - Little, Brown and Company: Kissinger Book, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 3439, Folder 27)
    - Little, Brown and Company: Legal, 1968-1974 (Offsite-box 3439, Folder 28)
    - Little, Brown and Company: Legal [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
    - Little, Brown and Company: Personnel, 1970-1985 (Offsite-box 3439, Folder 29-30)
    - Little, Brown and Company: Personnel [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
    - Little, Brown and Company: Possible Buyers, 1983-1986 (Offsite-box 3439, Folder 31)
    - Little, Brown and Company: Trade Department, 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 3439, Folder 32)
    - Museum Collections, Inc.: General, 1982-1983 (Offsite-box 3440, Folder 1)
    - Museum Collections, Inc.: Advance Announcements, 1982 (Offsite-box 3440, Folder 2)
    - Museum Collections, Inc.: Bronzes Ordered, 1978-1981 (Offsite-box 3440, Folder 3)
    - Museum Collections, Inc.: Close Down, 1983-1984 (Offsite-box 3440, Folder 4)
    - Museum Collections, Inc.: Correspondence with Fred Schulenburg, 1982-1984 (Offsite-box 3440, Folder 5)
    - Museum Collections, Inc.: Filler Ads and Space Bank, 1982-1983 (Offsite-box 3440, Folder 6)
    - Museum Collections, Inc.: Financial Reports, 1982 (Offsite-box 3440, Folder 7-8)
    - Museum Collections, Inc.: Income Statements, 1983 (Offsite-box 3440, Folder 9)
    - Museum Collections, Inc.: New York Graphic Society, 1982-1983 (Offsite-box 3440, Folder 10)
    - Museum Collections, Inc.: Products, 1978-1983 (Offsite-box 3440, Folder 11-15)
    - Museum Collections, Inc.: Sale, 1982-1987 (Offsite-box 3440, Folder 16)
    - Museum Collections, Inc.: Sale [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
    - New York Graphic Society: General, 1971-1982 (Offsite-box 3440, Folder 17-23)
    - New York Graphic Society: Alva Museum Replicas: General, 1969-1979 (Offsite-box 3440, Folder 24-28)
    - New York Graphic Society: Alva Museum Replicas: General, 1980-1981 (Offsite-box 3441, Folder 1-3)
    - New York Graphic Society: Alva Museum Replicas: Catalogs, 1978-1980 (Offsite-box 3441, Folder 4)
    - New York Graphic Society: Board of Directors, 1974 (Offsite-box 3441, Folder 5)
    - New York Graphic Society: Personnel, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 3441, Folder 6)
    - Oxmoor House, 1985-1986 (Offsite-box 3441, Folder 7)
    - Seven Arts and Book Find, 1969 (Offsite-box 3441, Folder 8)
    - Silver Burdett, 1973-1982 (Offsite-box 3441, Folder 9-10)
      The Silver Burdett files include materials on other educational publisher subsidiaries General Learning Corporation and Scott, Foresman.
    - Silver Burdett [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R64)
    - Stonehenge Press, 1979-1982 (Offsite-box 3441, Folder 11-12)
    - Time-Life Books, Inc.: Board of Directors and Board Meetings, 1976-1980 (Offsite-box 3441, Folder 13-19)
    - Time-Life Books, Inc.: Board of Directors and Board Meetings, 1981 (Offsite-box 3442, Folder 1-2)
    - Time-Life Home Video Club, 1986 (Offsite-box 3442, Folder 3)
    - Time-Life Travel Club, 1970-1973 (Offsite-box 3442, Folder 4-5)
- Series II. Books and Arts Associates Records, 1969-1980, 2015; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  Historical Note
  In 1965, Time Inc. became interested in investing in foreign publishing companies. By October 1966, they had made their first deal and purchased interest in Organizacion Editorial Novaro S.A., a leading Mexican magazine and book publisher. At this same time, Time-Life International executives were meeting with publishers in Germany looking for further investments. Ultimately Time Inc. purchased part of Rowohlt Taschenbuch Verlag. Two years later, Time Inc. purchased interest in Andre Deutsch Ltd, a British publishing house, and entered a joint venture with Spanish publisher Salvat Editores S.A. to distribute books and records directly by mail.
  In 1969 Time Inc. created a new entity to monitory its growing number of foreign investments called Books and Arts Associates (BAA). BAA's 1981-1985 strategic plan defines BAA as an advisory management consulting team. The earliest mention of BAA in Time Inc.'s annual reports states it contained the wholly-owned subsidiaries of the publishing house of Little, Brown and Company, the New York Graphic Society Ltd. (NYGS), "the largest publisher of fine-art reproductions in the world" along with its subsidiary Alva Museum Replicas, Inc., "which has exclusive reproduction rights to hundreds of museum artifacts" as well as the foreign publishing firms in which Time Inc. owned minority interests. Along with overseeing the investments made prior to its creation, BAA also managed investments in the French Editions Robert Laffont and Japanese Shingakusha-Time International as well as the 1978 joint venture Time Inc. entered with Little, Brown in France and Japan that focused on publishing materials in the medical field (Medsi). Zachary Morfogen, formerly an executive in Time Life International and then director of marketing for the Books, Arts, and Recordings Group (precursor to the Books Group), is BAA's managing director,
  While BAA was listed as its own department on the Time Inc. department head lists, by 1975 it functioned as a member of the Books Group along with Time-Life Books and the Book-of-the-Month Club, Inc. overseen by group vice president Joan Manley. At this time, BAA no longer oversees Little, Brown and NYGS. The 1981 annual report has no mention of BAA, and a June 29, 1981 memorandum from Manley to Department Heads announces the reassignment of companies overseen by BAA. Managing Director of BAA Europe Hans Bergmans continued handling the European minority holdings, but there is no mention of Bergmans in the department head lists past 1981. An August 7, 1981 memorandum from Denise Crockett to Manley's executive assistant Joan Berk refers to the Books Group as the office of record for BAA. A 1982 staff memo announces Morfogen joining Corporate Public Affairs.
  Pendergast, Curtis and Geoffrey Colvin. The World of Time Inc.:The Intimate History of a Changing Enterprise 1960-1980 (New York: Atheneum, 1986).
  Time Inc. 1980 Annual Report. 1981. http://www.thehistorycenteronline.com/collections/entry/category/annual-reports-time-inc.-temple-eastex, accessed June 2, 2017.
  The Books and Arts Associates Records cover the period of 1970 through 1981 and focus on the finances of Books and Arts Associates, a group within Time Inc. which monitored Time Inc.'s minority investments in foreign publishing houses. The majority of documents were created by or sent to Zachary Morfogen, the Managing Director of Books and Arts Associates. Included are newsletters along with printing invoices, strategic plans, budget reports, monthly and weekly operating reports, business objectives, account statements, international investment strategies, accounting policies and procedures, presentations on finances and income, and correspondence. The correspondence discusses social security benefits and payments, strategic plans, budgets, and operating reports.
  Arranged reverse chronologically as per the loose original order with undated material at the end.
  - Archives Transfer Form, 2015 (Offsite-box 786, Folder 1)
  - Strategic Plan: 1981-1985, 1980 (Offsite-box 786, Folder 2)
  - Weekly/Monthly Reports, 1980 (Offsite-box 786, Folder 3-6)
  - Budget, 1979 (Offsite-box 786, Folder 7)
  - Five-Year Plan: 1979-1983, 1978 (Offsite-box 786, Folder 8)
  - Summary of Accounting Policies and Procedures, 1978 (Offsite-box 786, Folder 11)
  - Plan and Budget, 1977 (Offsite-box 786, Folder 9-10)
  - Five Year Plan: 1978-1982, 1977 (Offsite-box 786, Folder 12)
  - Budget, 1976 (Offsite-box 786, Folder 13-14)
  - Two Year Plan: 1977-1978, 1976 (Offsite-box 786, Folder 15-16)
  - Budget, 1975 (Offsite-box 786, Folder 17)
  - Two-Year Plan: 1976-1977, 1975 (Offsite-box 786, Folder 18)
  - Budget, 1974 (Offsite-box 786, Folder 19)
  - International Investment Strategy, 1974 (Offsite-box 786, Folder 20)
  - Budget, 1973 (Offsite-box 786, Folder 21)
  - Newsletters, 1973 (Offsite-box 786, Folder 22-24)
  - Three Year Plan: 1974-1976, 1973 (Offsite-box 1834, Folder 1)
  - Budget, 1972 (Offsite-box 1834, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1972 (Offsite-box 1834, Folder 3-4)
  - Two-Year Plan, 1972 (Offsite-box 1834, Folder 5)
  - Budget, 1971 (Offsite-box 1834, Folder 6)
  - Five Year Plan, 1971 (Offsite-box 1834, Folder 7-8)
  - Newsletters, 1971 (Offsite-box 1834, Folder 9-14)
  - Newsletters, 1970 (Offsite-box 1834, Folder 15-22)
  - Newsletters, 1969 (Offsite-box 1834, Folder 23-26)
  - Financial Presentation, undated (Offsite-box 1834, Folder 27)
- Series III. Time-Life Records / Time-Life Music Series, 1966-1988; 3.25 Linear feet in 4 record cartons and 1 flat box
  The majority of materials in the Time-Life Records / Time-Life Music Series are booklets and liner notes that accompanied the reissued recordings sent out to subscribers. While the music on the albums was not recorded specifically for Time-Life Records, the booklets and liner notes contain unique editorial content created by Time-Life Books staff or by contracted experts. The Beethoven Bicentennial Collection has what looks like copies of the original liner notes created by Deutsche Grammophon and the Beethoven Archive Bonn. This series also includes some samples of the cassettes and CDs produced. Unreformatted audiovisual material in the collection is not accessible.
  Citation:
  Hooper, Bill. Email to Holly Deakyne, September 3, 2019. September 3.
  Organized alphabetically by series name.
  - American Musicals, 1981-1982 (Offsite-box 3442, Folder 6-8)
  - As You Remember Them, 1973 (Offsite-box 3442, Folder 9)
  - Arthur Fiedler's Favorites, 1977-1981 (Offsite-box 3442, Folder 10-11)
  - Beethoven Bicentennial Collection, circa 1971 (Offsite-box 3442, Folder 12)
  - The Beethoven Collection [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box 2868)
    Contains commercially packaged audiovisual material from this Time-Life Music subscription series. Components of the series include Piano Concerto No. 5, Symphonies 4 to 9, and Violin Concerto in D.
    6 audiocassettes: analog, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape.
  - Big Bands, 1983-1986 (Offsite-box 3325, Folder 1)
  - Concerts of Great Music, 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 3442, Folder 13-14)
  - Country Music, 1981 (Offsite-box 3443, Folder 1)
  - Country Western Classics, 1981-1983 (Offsite-box 3443, Folder 2-3)
  - The Gershwin Collection, 1974 (Offsite-box 3325, Folder 2)
  - Giants of Jazz, 1981-1982 (Offsite-box 3443, Folder 4-8)
  - Great Composers [RESTRICTED], 1988 (Offsite-box 2868)
    Contains commercially packaged audiovisual material from this Time-Life Music subscription series. Components of the series include an A cassette and B cassette each for Bach, Beethoven, Mozart and Tchaikovsky; and an A disc and B disc for Chopin.
    8 audiocassettes: analog, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape.
    2 compact discs (CD).
  - Great Men of Music, 1974-1979 (Offsite-box 3443, Folder 9-10)
  - Great Performers, 1981-1982 (Offsite-box 3444, Folder 1)
  - Metropolitan Centennial Collection of Great Opera, 1981-1983 (Offsite-box 3444, Folder 2-3)
  - Mozart, 1979-1982 (Offsite-box 3444, Folder 4-5)
  - The Mozart Collection [RESTRICTED], 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 2868)
    Contains commercially packaged audiovisual material from this Time-Life Music subscription series.
    22 audiocassettes: analog, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape.
  - The Rock 'n' Roll Era, 1986-1988 (Offsite-box 3444, Folder 6)
  - The Story of Great Music, 1966-1972 (Offsite-box 3444, Folder 7-8)
  - The Story of Great Music, 1966-1972 (Offsite-box 3325, Folder 3)
  - The Story of Great Music [RESTRICTED], circa 1972 (Offsite-box 2868)
    Contains commercially produced audiovisual material from this Time-Life Records subscription series.
    3 audiocassettes: analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On label: The Story of Great Music-The Spanish Style."
  - The Swing Era, 1985 (Offsite-box 3444, Folder 9)
- Series IV. Iran Publishing Project Files, 1971-1986; 3 Linear feet in 4 record cartons
  Sherkate Chap va Nashreh Danesheh Now (Danesheh Now, sometimes called Daneshe Now) formed in 1976, but did not start operations until 1978. The idea for the educational publishing venture originated with the Empress Farah and her Special Bureau and was funded by the Industrial and Mining Development Bank of Iran. The venture contracted Time Inc. to perform initial studies as early as 1971 to determine if there was enough demand in Iran for a new publishing company. Time Inc. was also to provide book licensing, expert assistance and staff training staff. According to The World of Time Inc., Time Inc. was chosen because of president James Linen's long acquaintance with the Shah.
  From the records, it looks like Washington-based Time-Life Books executive Robert Ellis was in charge of this project with Iradj Bagherzade, previously of Time-Life Books Europe, as the on-site project director. Danesheh Now published thirteen books in 1978. In November 1978, because of the unrest in Iran, the remaining Time Inc. employees left the country. Time Inc. later filed a claim with the Iran-United States Claims Tribunal regarding payment for services. White and Case was the legal representative.
  Prendergast, Curtis, and Geoffrey Colvin. 1986. The World of Time Inc.: The Intimate History of a Changing Enterprise, 1960-1980. New York: Atheneum.
  United States. 1977. "Iran: a survey of U.S. business opportunities." [Washington]: U.S. Dept. of Commerce, Domestic and International Business Administration, Bureau of International Commerce. https://archive.org/details/iransurveyofusbu00unit
  The Iran Publishing Project Files include records on this contract project undertaken by Time Inc. and staffed by Time-Life Books employees. The majority of files looks like they came from the supervising Time-Life Books executive Robert Ellis. Records include the initial studies, invoices submitted by Time Inc. to Danesheh Now, correspondence with on-site project director Iradj Bagherzade, and court records from the claim filed by Time Inc. with the Iran-United States Claims Tribunal.
  - Archives Transfer Memoranda, 1980, 1986 (Offsite-box 3708, Folder 29)
  - Danesheh Now: Company Registration, 1976 (Offsite-box 3708, Folder 30)
  - Ellis, Robert: To Be Filed, 1979 (Offsite-box 3708, Folder 31)
  - Finances: Iranian Bank Account, 1978-1980 (Offsite-box 3708, Folder 32-33)
  - Initial Studies, 1971, 1975 (Offsite-box 3708, Folder 34-35)